I don't understand what's going wrong. Productivity has dropped, employees
are slacking off, and some have even started leaving.
I've been reviewing the situation. The issue may be
linked to how we are managing our human resources.
But everything is structured efficiently. Tasks are clearly defined and
employees know exactly what to do. Isn't that enough?
That reflects the rational approach — focusing on efficiency and
task performance. But it doesn't address motivation or satisfaction.
So are you saying the rational approach isn't
sufficient for managing human resources in this organization?
Exactly. Why do we need the behavioral approach when the
rational approach already ensures efficiency? That's the real question.
I always thought if employees were trained
properly, they would just do their jobs.
Employees are not just workers — they have needs, expectations,
and emotions. Ignoring these leads to disengagement and resignation.
So the issue — employees slacking off and leaving
— could be due to ignoring the behavioral aspects?
Yes. That's why we must examine if the rational approach alone is
enough, or if the behavioral approach is necessary for long-term success.
I see your point. Efficiency is important, but we also need to
focus on motivation and well-being to improve performance and retain staff.